Polisar, Eric Papers /3035
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Eric Polisar Papers
1965-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Polisar, Eric
/3035
23 cubic feet
23 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Professor Polisar's papers mostly concerning Civil Rights, public employment, and workplace discrimination. Also includes materials for the ILR courses he taught.
7924529
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 02, 2013
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, May 08, 2023
Biographical / Historical
Eric Polisar (June 29, 1923 July 31, 1968) was a member of the faculty at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of the University of Wisconsin (BA, 1949; MA, 1950), Polisar taught at the New York State Teachers College at New Paltz before joining the Extension Division of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1952. From 1953 to 1961, he worked on the staff of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. He returned to the Cornell faculty in 1961 and remained on the faculty until his death in 1968.
See the Cornell University Memorial Faculty Statement for Professor Eric Polisar: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18855
Scope and Contents
Key to abbrevations in the papers:
OCB - The Office of Collective Bargaining
UFT - United Federation of Teachers
AFSCME - Ameriacn Federaton of State and Municipal Employees
PERB - Public Employment Relations Board
ACWA - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
IAM - International Association of Machinists
I.U.D. Industrial Union Department, AFL-CIO
IUE - International Unino of Electric, Radio, and Machine Workers
SIU - Seafarer's International Union
SSEU - Social Services Employee Union
JLC - Joint Legislation Committee
SCHR - State Commission for Human Rights (commonly references NYS)
CCR - US Commission of Civil Rights
FEP - Fair Employment Practices
EEOC: Equal Employment Opportunity Commission
PPA- Public Personnel Administration
OFCC - Office of Federal Contract Compliance
EEO - Equal Employment Opportunity
IBEW - International Brotherhood of Elcectrical Workers
I.C.F.T.U. - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3012: Alice Cook Papers /3042m: George W. Brooks Papers /3051: Albert Martin Papers /4014: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files /4014: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files /4283: ILR School Extension Division (Buffalo, N.Y.) Files 6047: Archives Information File /4347: George W. Brooks Collections
Polisar, Eric
7924529
- Includes files on civil rights and employment. (Box 1)
  - Roy Draft (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Korman Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Syracuse Public Health Nurse Dispute (Fran Milberg), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Draft Report and Pacific Report, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Books, Pamphlets and Articles Re Civil Rights, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Books, Pamphlets and Articles Re Civil Rights, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reflecting on the New Left - Pull Bullock (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondences Re Report, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Research Project In South to Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Polisar - Ohio, Detroit Papers, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Riots and The Law. Who Enforces which, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Executive Order 10988 Theory and Practice (L.M. Brochman), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Civil Rights Projects - NYC Extension, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Civil Rights Training Projects (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence on Possible Workshops, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fayette County Project, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - East Harlem Project, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Course On Rights, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Proposed Lecture Series, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Housing - Information Re Negro Housing, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Economic Status of Negro - Miscellaneous Material, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A Proposal For Obtaining Federal Civil Rights Legislation (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Scope and Contents
    Documents probably from 1964
  - Yearly Budgets of the Commissions Against Discrimination in the State (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Civil Rights Newsletter, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - List of Books on Civil Rights - Memo to Mackinyre, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - News Clippings (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Reviews, Reports, Proposals, Letters, etc, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence Re Manuscript on Civil Rights and Employment, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Civil Rights Manuscript Second Draft (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Relation Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- School memos, papers and bulletins; file on Politics and rioting; Wayne Conference Report, 1967; Pittsburgh Ordinance 1967; Kaufman "American Liberalism and Black Power" Michigan 5/67 (Box 2)
  - Paper Bulletins, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Mail, magazines, and articles
  - Paper Bulletins, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Paper Bulletins, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes Transmittal Slips
  - Proposals, Pamphlets, Letters, etc.., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Leadership Conference On Civil Rights Bulletins, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - AFL-CIO News, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Newspapers (May - August)
  - The Public Employee Press, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Newspapers (April - July)
  - Labor News, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Newspaper (May-August)
  - The Advance, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Newspapers (May- June)
  - School Memos, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Accts. Of Social and Economic Injustice" Rebellions" by Region (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Regions: Far West, East, NY, South, Chicago, and Cleveland
  - Industrial and Labor Relations Reviews, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Proposals, Letters, Concerns, etc, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Includes: calendar and a photo document
  - Kaufman - American, Liberalism and Black Power, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Michigan, May'67
  - Proposals, Pamphlets, Letters, etc, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - News Clippings, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - News Clippings, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - News Clippings, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Wayne Conference, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    May
  - Proposals, Letters, Agreements, etc (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Pittsburgh Ordinances, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Politics and Rioting: News Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Politics and Rioting: News Clippings, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Politics and Rioting: News Clippings, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence 1963-67; expense accounts; seminar reports, various info files on agriculture, apprenticeship, arbitration; bibliographies, book reviews, Buffalo, collective bargaining, disarmament, Eleanor Roosevelt, labor education, labor history Minevil (Box 3)
  - Labor Markets and Unemployment Rates: A Strange Case, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sweet Corn Quality Conference(Misc. Info) - Agriculture, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Re Apprenticeship Training, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Memo to Files: Apprentice Training, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Material. Re Apprentice Training, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - How to alienate Arbitrators and Lose Cases, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Labor Topics: Mobility, Wage Inflexibility, Labor Movement, and Collective Bargaining (Box 3, Folder 7)
    One document is seems to be dated (1963)
  - Bibliographies, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Book Reviews, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Buffalo, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Buffalo Economics, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Buffalo Economics, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Expenses, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Past Programs in Labor and Management, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ethics and Responsible Leadership, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    October 30th - 31st
  - Future Seminars: Meeting with Leonard Aries rel Weinberg Seminar, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    May.3rd
  - Weinberg Seminar, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Weinberg Seminar, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    November - December
  - Correspondence - Speeches, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - AFT Seminar: Civil Rights, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Public Employees And the Right to Strike, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    May-November
  - WURF Speech - BTUC, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Negroes, the economy, politics, NYS, and the future, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    August
  - Urban League Speech, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - ASPA Welfare Strike and Public Employee Bargaining, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Senior Banquet, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Labor Movement and Civil Rights - Brooks, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Parents Weekend, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Parent's weekend in Willard Straight. April 24th.
  - Executive Development N.Y.C. Welfare Strike, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    June 5th
  - Welfare Costs and Tax Policy- A Study In Contradiction, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    December 2nd
  - Auburn Builders Exchange, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    News Clippings. Banquet Program.
  - Associated Building Contractors, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    January 27th.
  - Elmira Builders Exchange, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    February 12th.
  - Seminar in Executive Leadership and Discrimination in Employment, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Jut 15th.
  - First Universalist Church, Rochester, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    September 6th.
  - Labor and Manpower- ASPA Albany, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    October 13th.
  - Union Conventions-Alice Cook's Class, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Unions and Agriculture, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - The story of ILGWU - Home Economics - Cornell, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Buffalo C of C - Breakfast Club, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Outlook for Niagara Frontier, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Pamphlets, Papers, Etc. on disarmament, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Cornell Daily Sun newspaper
  - Collective Bargaining, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    Misc. materials. A document from 1962
  - Correspondence Re Disarmament, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Foundation, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Labor Education, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Labor History, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Mineville Study (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous Period - ICALS, Pamphlets, announcements etc., 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous Period - ICALS, pamphlets, announcements etc. (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Includes Local 371 study and general office files (Box 4)
  - AFSCME Council 50, AFL-CIO, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Newspaper.
  - AFSCME Council 50, AFL-CIO, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 16th International Convention - AFSCME, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Michigan State Council 7 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - District Council 7 - Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - NY District Council 37 - Constitution, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - NY District Council 37 - Constitution, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    NY C Transit Agreement. NYC and AFSCME Agreement.
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Memorandums and other Correspondence- Council 50 Project, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Memo to files- Council 50, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Program - "Organizational Policies and Procedures" - Charge Program Fees, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Council 50 - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Welfare Local 371 - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 371 Dictation, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Copy of Agreements, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Local 371 Survey, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    May. Newspaper.
  - Local 371 Financial Report, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 371 State Executive Board, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 371 Contract Compliance, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 371 and S.S.E.P.R., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Newspapers. Social Services Employees Union.
  - 14th International Convention - AFSCME, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    April 27th - May 1st
  - Welfare Local 371 AFSCME Constitution, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Welfare Local 371 - Misc. Material, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Canal Zone - Correspondence Re Canal Zone, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Expenses - Correspondences, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Accumulated Notes, Work Schedule, and Participants, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Material - Contracts, Canal Zone, Pamphlets, etc., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - AFSCME Constitutions, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence Re Constitution, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Includes: Award of Service to Polisar
  - Preamble Report of Constitution, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Preamble AFSCME Constitution, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Article II Objectives, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Suggestions for Revision - AFSCME Constitution, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Notes to File - State, County, and Municipal Workers Constitution, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Draft Proposals - Workers Preamble and Bill of Rights (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Includes civil rights materials (Box 5)
  - Misc. Materials- State Commission for Human Rights, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - US Commission on Human Rights, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Requests for Statement, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Youngstown Civil Rights Commission, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes: newspapers
  - Equal Employment Opportunity-Conference Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Bulletin - Equal Employment: Law and Reality, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights - Bulletins, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights - Bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights - Bulletins, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Seminar on Manpower Policy and Program - Brookings Institution, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Seminar on Manpower Policy and Program, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - NYACK Conference on Unemployment and Social Change, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Includes: articles, and pamphlets
  - White House Conference - "To Fulfill These Rights", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - White House Conference - Programs, list of participants, and councils' report, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights Seminar, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rochester - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Announcements - Rochester, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Includes: graph/map and newspapers
  - The Negro, Economy, Civil Rights Law, and the Future, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Negro, Economy, Civil Rights Law, and the Future, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Material - Rochester (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Rochester Project, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Anti-Poverty Program, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Civil Rights Research - Rochester, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Rochester, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Draft Report on Research in Public Hearing, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Randolph vs. ILA Local 791, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Civil Rights Manuscripts (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Various PERB, arbitration and fact-finding material, 1967-68; includes information on the NYC Welfare Strike (Box 6)
  - NYS Governor's Panel - Public Employee Collective Bargaining, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Assembly of Governmental Employees with Affiliated Unions, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - California Court Decision - Welfare, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Court Review of State Unit Decision, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey Commission Recommendations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Detroit Police Fact-Finding, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Rosenzweig - The Condon - Waldin Act Re-examined, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - NYC Council Legislation - Re: OCB, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    OCB - Office of Collective Bargaining
  - NYC - OCB Executive Order, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    OCB- Office of Collective Bargaining
  - Expenses Other then School, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Expenses Other than School, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - NYC - OCB Legislation, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - NYS Rossetti Bill, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Milwaukee AFSCME Agreement, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - NYC Executive Order #49 and Regulations, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Comparisons - State Legislation (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - NYC-AFSCME-IBT Decision, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Milwaukee Grievance and Arbitration Procedure (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Hawaii Employee Management Cooperation Act, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Missouri Act- Bargaining Bill, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Michigan Mediation Decision on Agency Shop, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Michigan Security, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Mt. Vernon Fact-Finding Report, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Rockefeller - CSEA Recognition, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    November
  - Rochester Teacher Salaries Fact0Finding Report, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Role of Neutral in Grievance Arbitration - Eli Rock, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - NYS Analysis of Apprenticeship Section Standards, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Public Employment Relations Board (PERB) - Amityville, NY (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - NYS Public Employment Relations Board(PERB) Hearings - AFSCME, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    September
  - NYS Public Employment Relations Board (PERB) News, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - PERB State Wide Unit Decision, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - PERB Unit Determination (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - NYS Court of Appeals - RE: PERB, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - PERB - United Federation of Teachers (UFT) Penalties, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - PERB - Statement of Procedures under Fair Employment Act (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Pittsburgh of Education Response To Teachers' Federation, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Rhode Island - Municipal Arbitration Act, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - United Federation of Teachers (UFT) Contract, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - State Labor Laws, 1960-1967 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Theodore Kheel report on Taylor Law, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Taylor Law and PERB Rules, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    Includes: A newspaper
  - Tarshes' Labor Policy - County Gov't, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Public Employees' Fair Employment Act, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Public Employees' Fair Employment Act, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority(TVA) Contract, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - U.S. Experience in Collective Bargaining in Public Employment - Arvid Anderson, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - OCB - Arvid Anderson, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - NYC Tri-partite Public, Union position, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - NYC Tri-partite Report, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - NYC Welfare Strike and Summary, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    Includes: Newspapers
  - NYC Welfare Strikes Rosenzweig, Foster Papers, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Includes Polisar papers and articles and civil rights materials (Box 7)
  - LR Strikes and Solutions - Eric Polisar, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Polisar Bulletin, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Polisar Bulletin Reader's Comments, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Polisar Bulletin Reader's Comments, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Polisar Bulletin Reader's Comments, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Polisar Northrop/Rowan Review, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Includes: Journal of Human Resources
  - Polisar Poverty Article, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights Speeches, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Local 28 Article: Employment Discrimination and The Building Case (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Papers and Reports: Apprentice Training and Equal Opportunity Law, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Polisar - Testimony, Civil Rights Commission, N.Y.C., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut Commission on Civil Rights, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Includes: Cards and pamphlets
  - Mt. Vernon, NY Commission on Human Rights, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Nebraska Equal Opportunity Commission, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Demographic Change and Racial Ghettos: American Cities' Crisis, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Housing Integration in an Age of "White Backlash" and "Black Power" (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Council 50 - Statement to PERB (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - AFL-CIO Council 50: Leaflets and Publications, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Includes: Posters, newspaper, and union pins
  - AFL-CIO Council 50 - Leaflets and Publications, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Includes: Posters and newspapers
  - Membership Statistics and Propaganda/Posters, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Member Statistics, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Survey of Opinion: Among Employees of Mental Institutions (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Civil Service Commission, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Civil Service Commission Equal Opportunity, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Memphis Sanitation Strike, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - ALF-CIO Council 50 - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Includes: Posters, stickers, & pamphlets
- ILR course materials; correspondence; committee meetings and other misc. (Box 8)
  - Tri-County Long Island Labor Management Institute (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - University Labor Education Association (ULEA), 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Semi-Annual Reports
  - University Labor Education Association, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Quarterly Reports
  - University Labor Education Association Meetings, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - University Labor Education Association, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Steering Committee Meeting
  - Acting Dean Robert Risley, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Report of Discussion
  - University Labor Education Association Annual Meeting, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Discussion Paper on Multi-University Projects. April.
  - University Labor Education Association, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    April
  - University Labor Education Association - Material Projects, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - University Labor Education Association - Correspondence, 1962-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - USA Record - Uniformed Sanitation Association, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Conference of Mayor, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - W.E. Upjohn Institute, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - ILR 100/200, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - ILR 120/220, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Fall
  - ILR 250, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    NYC, Spring
  - ILR 250 - Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - ILR 250, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Fall Courses
  - ILR 250 - Questionnaires, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - ILR 250 - Rough Draft Questionnaires, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - ILR 250 - Final Exam - Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - ILR 250 - Grading, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - ILR 250 - Surveying of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - ILR 300, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Summer
  - ILR 300 - Reading List, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - ILR 300, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Includes: Newspaper ILR documents
  - ILR 400-501 - Collective Bargaining Structures, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - ILR 400, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - ILR 402, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    Includes: Registration Cards
  - ILR 402, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - ILR 402, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - ILR 507, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - ILR 507 - Theories of the Labor Management, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Spring. Rosters. Registration cards.